DANIEL DOVAL

Senior Software Engineer

SW 98th Ter Miami FL Miami , Florida, 33186 daniel.doval.1992@gmail.com 18044643529

Senior Go Engineer focused on the microservice architecture.

Strong understanding of the several distributed tools/libraries for the wide-range of purposes.

Experienced with the Agile methodology with many of the tools, and have strong communication skills and management skills with different size of software development team.

Professional Experience

November 2019 -May 2022 Back End Developer

Wallet Max

- $\bullet \quad \text{Designed the infrastructure of the financial product with Golang microservice architecture.} \\$
- Containerized the microservices by using Docker/Kubernetes/Amazon EKS, ECS.
- · Used the Apache Kafka for Real time payment system.
- Monitoring services with Prometheus, Cloud Watch, etc.
- Developed the Apis by combining gRPC and Restful methodology.
- · Implemented CI/CD with CircleCi with Unit testing.
- Designed the Postgresql database.
- · Attended frontend development with React.JS.

February 2017 -August 2019

Backend Developer

Turing

- Responsible for development and guidance junior developers in the technical stacks: NodeJS, ReactJS, MongoDB, AWS Recognition, AWS S3, AWS Lambda.
- · Responsible for development of backend apis in Golang.
- Implemented load-balancing with nginx to allow NodeJS instances to handle concurrent users.
- Built RESTAPIs, CRUD operations, HTTP methods, JWT & Refresh tokens.
- Node.js, MongoDB with Mongoose, TypeScript and Express & express middleware
- Used MySQL and NoSQL on the backend
- Worked closely with System Administrators to take ownership of the product's operations and metrics
- Worked on RESTful API design and development
- Partnering with teammates to discuss about solutions
- Responsible for suggestion of the best solutions to scale the product

January 2015 -January 2017

Full stack Developer

Rhino

- Implemented front-end scalable architecture using the MVC model, decoupling responsibilities and reusable components.
- Introduced React to the front-end stack and developed reusable components along with Google Material Design components.
- Redesigned the home page, product detail pages, and listing pages with new business logic and REST API implementation
- Improved page load performance and best practices using vanilla JS with ES6 and Babel.
- Developed a mock PWA application with Angular 7 and introduced PWA capabilities to the company
- Introduced and presented Drupal CMS as an improvement for our content management with decoupled Drupal and REST API

Education

Bachelor's Degree in ComputerScience University of Florida

April 2010 - August 2014

Key Skills

- Golang microservice architecture with concurrent programming
- Containerization with Docker/Kubernetes/AWS EKS/ECS
- SQL/NO SQL Programming
- Restful API development (HTTP, gRPC)
- Data/Event streaming with Apache Kafka/Amazon SQS
- Big Data Processing with Apache Spark + Apache Kafka
- Monitoring Service development with Prometheus
- Experienced CI/CD pipeline with Unit testing
- Frontend development with React.JS
- Agile/Scrum development